Mohamed Hosam

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Tepeköy Mah. izmit, Kocaeli, Turkey

□ (+90) 552-540-1591 | ■ mohamedhosaaam154@gmail.com | ★ m4hosam.com | ᡚ m4hosam | the m4hosam

Summary.

Over the last 3 years, i have built several projects with different programming languages. Currently, I am leveraging the power of AI with tools like ChatGPT and Github Copilot to code at 5x speed and learning system architecture, design patterns, and contributing to open-source projects. I believe in writing clean, well-documented code to help the team work more efficiently. Looking forward to discussing more in an interview.

Experience ____

Freelance Remotely

NEXTJS DEVELOPER

July 2023 - Present

- Collaborated directly with clients to gather requirements and translate them into system specifications, ensuring alignment with project goals and objectives.
- Developed a high-performance e-commerce website from scratch using Next.js. Implemented an intuitive admin dashboard for efficient order management and comprehensive sales reporting. Preview
- Created an Intelligent Lighting Distribution Planner that automates lighting distribution based on room dimensions, ensuring rapid response and enhanced user experience Preview

Metal Maker 3D Krakow, Poland

PYTHON SOFTWARE ENGINEER (ERASMUS INTERN)

July 2023 - September 2023

- Led a team of interns at in developing a plugin for UltiMaker Cura 3D printing software, automating sprue generation for metal parts, drastically reducing design time from 3-5 hours to less than 5 minutes. MetalMaker3D
- Organized the project by breaking it down into manageable tasks, ensuring each team member had a well-defined role and responsibility. Leveraged Agile Methodology and GitHub for task management, fostering collaboration and transparency among team members.
- Contributed to the company's goal of enhancing 3D printing capabilities, delivering a valuable tool for UltiMaker Cura 3D software, significantly improving efficiency and user experience in part production.

Kocaeli University Labs

Kocaeli, Turkey

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Jun. 2022 - Nov. 2022

- Developed Food Scholarship Website using ASP.Net MVC for student applications.
- Built a user-friendly scholarship application form, validating user inputs during submission.
- Ensured robust student login and authentication for secure scholarship application access.
- Designed an intuitive application view page, enabling students to manage submissions.
- Implemented mandatory field validation controls in the application form for data accuracy.
- Proactively addressed and resolved post-deployment bugs and student issues.

Skills

Programming Python, TypeScript, C, Node.js, Bash/Linux

Back-end MongoDB, MYSQL, RESTful API, Express, Flask, Prisma, SQLAlchemyFront-end NextJS, ReactJS, HTML/CSS/Javascript, Tailwind CSS, WordPress, Jest

Others Git/GitHub, Agile/SCRUM, Debugging, Unit Testing, OOP, Design Patterns, System Design, Machine learning, Data Structure

Languages Arabic, English, Turkish

Education

Kocaeli University

Kocaeli, Turkey

Sep. 2020 - May 2024

B.S. IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

• Turkey Merit Scholarship Holder. GPA of 3.5. Erasmus+ Internship Recipient